<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Art | Make. Family. Fun.]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.makefamilyfun.ca/blog/categories/art/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.makefamilyfun.ca/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-08T23:57:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.makefamilyfun.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Julian Rendell & Sarah Dakin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the Wonders of Wood- PechaKucha Richmond]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.makefamilyfun.ca/blog/2015/05/08/discover-the-wonders-of-wood-pechakucha-richmond/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-08T18:09:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.makefamilyfun.ca/blog/2015/05/08/discover-the-wonders-of-wood-pechakucha-richmond</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love wood. I love warm sunsets. I love being near water. And it&rsquo;s all better when in a beautiful heritage building with glittering live classical guitar.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sitting in the Chinese Bunkhouse at the Britannia Shipyards National Historic Site, about to listen to a <a href="http://www.pechakucha.org/">PechaKucha talk</a> about the <a href="http://www.richmond.ca/newsevents/city/DiscoverTheWondersOfWoodAtPechaKuchaRichmond.htm">Wonders of Wood</a>. I found out about it from a tweet by <a href="https://twitter.com/richmond_bc">@Richmond_BC</a>. I have no idea what <a href="http://www.pechakucha.org/">PechaKucha</a> is beyond the introductory paragraph in the <a href="http://www.richmond.ca/newsevents/city/DiscoverTheWondersOfWoodAtPechaKuchaRichmond.htm">invitation article</a> which described it as a series of speakers presenting 20 slides for no more than 20 seconds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>My assumption was that it would be similar to a round of lightning talks- in tech circles that would mean about 30-40 minutes for 10 speaker. So I was surprised to be told this is a 3 hour event. So unfortunately I&rsquo;ll only be able to see the first speaker or two.</p>

<p>Watching the slides going by right now as people drift in, there appears to be a depth and breadth of content to be presented that will easily fill the allotted time. And plenty of background conversations talking about various types of lumber.</p>

<p>And after four talks, or half the event, I had to go.</p>

<p>But I did get to see a presentation by designers who had worked with, if memory serves, the Canadian Wood Council to show wood can be used to build six story buildings. They also highlighted it&rsquo;s inviting appearance and low cost.</p>

<p>Then some amazing carvings by the <a href="http://richmondcarvers.com/">Richmond Carvers</a>.</p>

<p>This was followed by a personal talk by the founder of <a href="http://www.unionwoodco.com/">Union Wood</a> about how wood connects the past with the present, with an interesting aside into being a garbage man.</p>

<p>The last talk I got to see was by zoologist Hugh Griffith that explored non-human users of wood- insects, birds, and animals.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.pechakucha.org/">Pecha Kucha</a> is a great template and <a href="http://www.pechakucha.org/cities/richmond-bc">Pecha Kucha Richmond</a> has a pool of talented presenters. Now I understand the format I&rsquo;ll be prepared for next time!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
